Guide to the Jonathan Leiss papers, 1960-2008 RL.11595
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jonathan Leiss papers
1960-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Leiss, Jonathan
Phelps, John Julian, 1935-
RL.11595
0.75 Linear Feet
Collection includes 15 oral history interviews on 19 audio-cassette tapes, interview transcripts, and other papers related to Leiss's research on Duke University administrator Jon Julian "Jake" Phelps and his experiences during the Civil Rights movement in Durham, N.C. Interview subjects include Jake Phelps, Howard Clement, Floyd McKissick, Jr., Bill Griffith, Stephen Phelps, Peggy Manring, Wayne King, and Trudy Minnear Smith.
Biographical / Historical
Jonathan Leiss is a graduate of Bennington College in Vermont, 2006.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Jonathan Leiss papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007 and 2018.
Collection Overview
Collection includes 15 oral history interviews on 19 audio-cassette tapes, interview transcripts, and other papers related to Leiss's research on Duke University administrator Jon Julian "Jake" Phelps and his experiences during the Civil Rights movement in Durham, N.C. Interview subjects include Jake Phelps, Howard Clement, Floyd McKissick, Jr., Bill Griffith, Stephen Phelps, Peggy Manring, Wayne King, and Trudy Minnear Smith.
Conditions Governing Access
Use copies must be created before researchers may access the content of the original audiocassettes in the collection.
Civil rights movements -- North Carolina -- Durham; Durham (N.C.) -- Race relations; Audiocassettes; Leiss, Jonathan; Phelps, John Julian, 1935-; Clement, Arthur John Howard, III, 1934-2016; Mckissick, Floyd, Jr., 1952-; Griffith, William; Phelps, Stephen; Manring, Margaret, 1938-; King, Wayne, 1939-2017; Smith, Loretto Gertrude Minnear
- Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
- Clippings and printed materials, 1969-2004 and undated (Box 1)
- Freedom of information act requests, 1960-2008; 3 folders (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Redacted FBI files relating to sit-ins in North Carolina and to Jake Phelps military service. Includes correspondence between Leiss and the U.S. Department of Justice.
- Interview transcripts, 2002-2006; 2 folders (Box 1)
  Incomplete transcipts and notes taken by Jonathan Leiss. Bulk of transcipts are for his interviews with Jake Phelps.
- Phelps, John Julian (Jack) interviews, 2002 July 2-2006 February 6; 12 audiocassettes (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 1 Jake Phelps, 2002 July 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette FL11595-CS-0001)
  - Originial audio-cassette tape 2 Jake Phelps, 2002 July 2-18 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0002)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 3 Jake Phelps, 2002 July 18 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0003)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 4 Jake Phelps, 2002 August 13 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0004)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 5 Jake Phelps, 2002 August 24 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0005)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 6 Jake Phelps, 2004 January 30 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0006)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 7 Jake Phelps, 2004 February 3 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0007)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 8 Jake Phelps, 2004 February 3 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0008)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 9 Jake Phelps, 2006 January 15 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0009)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 10 Jake Phelps, 2006 February 5 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0010)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 11 Jake Phelps, 2006 February 5 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0011)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 12 Jake Phelps, 2006 February 5 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0012)
- Clement, Howard interview, 2006 February 10 (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 13 A.J. Howard Clement, 2006 February 10 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0013)
- Griffith, Bill interview, 2006 February 6 (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 14 Bill Griffith, 2006 February 6 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0014)
- King, Wayne interview, 2006 February 8 (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 15 Wayne King, 2006 February 8 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0015)
- Manring, Peggy interview, 2006 January 16 (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 16 Peggy Manring, 2006 January 16 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0016)
- McKissick, Floyd, Jr. interview, 2006 February 1 (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 17 Floyd McKissick, Jr., 2006 February 1 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0017)
- Phelps, Stephen interview, 2006 February 8 (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 18 Stephen Phelps, 2006 February 8 (Box 2)
- Smith, Trudy Minnear interview, 2006 February 3 (Box 2)
  - Original audio-cassette tape 19 Trudy Minnear Smith, 2006 February 3 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11595-CS-0019)